{
    "id": "3a06bea7699943ed8b28b7614c16a0df",
    "title": "Sentence Completion Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The mother was …………….. inside the house when the children started screaming.",
            "description": "Both hardly and scarcely are possible here.",
            "answers": [
                "hardly",
                "no sooner",
                "scarcely",
                "Either hardly or scarcely"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "It is the same everywhere ……………….. in India.",
            "description": "We cannot use except for before prepositions and conjunctions.",
            "answers": [
                "except",
                "except for",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t like their company. They talk ……………… rubbish.",
            "description": "We cannot use the article ‘a/an’ before uncountable nouns.",
            "answers": [
                "such",
                "such a",
                "such as"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I have got too much nose and not ………………",
            "description": "Chin is a noun. When enough modifies a noun, it goes before that noun.",
            "answers": [
                "chin enough",
                "enough chin",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Come in quietly ………………… she doesn’t hear you.",
            "description": "That can be left out in an informal style in some common two-word conjunctions, such as so that, such…that, now that etc.",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "so that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "…………….. is a lot of noise in the street.",
            "description": "In sentences which say that something exists somewhere we usually use 'there' as a kind of preparatory subject.",
            "answers": [
                "There",
                "It",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………. he was foreign made it difficult for him to get a job.",
            "description": "It is unusual for that-clauses to stand alone as subjects. They are more often introduced by the expression ‘the fact’.",
            "answers": [
                "That",
                "The fact",
                "The fact that"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Have you got anything ...................... belongs to me?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She wondered why he ………………. there.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we are more likely to use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I was very .....................… in the lesson.",
            "description": "We make the past continuous tense forms by putting 'was / were' before the -ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "interesting",
                "interested",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We ………………… by the immigration officer.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have questioned",
                "were questioned",
                "were questioning"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………….. in prison for life.",
            "description": "When the subject is not the doer of the action we use passive verb forms. In the simple past tense, passive forms are made by putting was/were before the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "has put",
                "was put",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}